MELISSA ANASTASIA

An Early Childhood Teacher with 10+ years of experience, specializing in child development, differentiated instruction, education technology, and early childhood literacy. A strong history of leading the integration of technology into the classroom to enhance student growth. Adept at tailoring instruction in alignment with individual learning needs.

123 Your Street, Providence, RI 12345 mel i ssaa n astasi a@exa m pl e.com (123) 456-7890

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LEAD EARLY CHILDHOOD TEACHER

Providence Preschool, Providence, RI September 2016 - Present

- Develop and implement innovative lesson plans for classrooms with up to 25
 preschool students, tailor instruction based on student strengths and weaknesses,
 and utilize cooperative learning activities to develop communication and
 relationship building skills
- Lead the integration of education technology across the preschool and provide training to preschool teachers to maintain quality instruction to students during Covid-19
- Manage five assistant preschool teachers and provide coaching and mentorship to 10+ certified preschool teachers to develop an engaging curriculum

EARLY CHILDHOOD TEACHER

Rhode Island Learning Center, Providence, RI September 2011 - June 2016

- Created engaging learning activities and curriculum to facilitate the growth of child literacy, which included differentiating instruction to improve understanding of language and expand child vocabulary
- Attended regular meetings with parents to facilitateongoingcommunication regarding the social, emotional, and cognitive development of students

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF EDUCATION (B.E.) EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION

University of Rhode Island, South Kingstown, RI September 2007- May 2011

KEY SKILLS

- Early Childhood Education
- Edu ratio n Techno logy
- Early Childhood Literacy
- · Curriculum Development
- Team Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

Preschool Teaching Certification.
 State of Rhode Island, 2016